Chukwuemeka Okpala

904 Asbury Terrace Philadelphia, PA 19126 menji16@hotmail.com 609-226-2421

Career Profile:

Protective Security Officer with 8 years experience working on a Department of Homeland Security contract. Possess a valid ACT 235 certified to carry a licensed firearm while working as a security officer. Also have experience working unarmed security posts at local WAWA stores throughout the Philadelphia area. Gained extensive leadership skills managing both small and large groups in the United States Marine Corps. I was responsible for executing plans involving convoy missions in a stressful combat environment.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

 Allied Universal 1617 JFK Blvd, Ste 960 Philadelphia, PA 19103 Mar 2021 – Present

I am required to patrol to various Bank of America ATM locations throughout the Philadelphia city area. Insuring that locations are secure, clean, free of any damage or vandalism, and no individuals loitering/sleeping on the premises. It is my duty report any such activities electronically and /or contact emergency services.

 Security Industry Specialists, Inc. 6071 Bristol Pkwy Culver City, CA 90230 Apr 2021 – Present

I am tasked with providing a visible deterrent against potential theft or mal behavior at a local branch of an international chain retail store. Furthermore, I am to report any such activities to the store supervisor on duty and call law enforcement for assistance (should the situation warrant it). It is my duty to observe and report any such occurrence that may be detrimental to store property or any persons within in the facility.

 Allied Universal 1617 JFK Blvd, Ste 960 Philadelphia, PA 19103 Apr 2021 – Sept 2021

I was tasked with screening national/international air cargo at the UPS airport hub. Using various approved screening methods, I am tasked with ensuring that all consignments entering or exiting the facility do not contain any prohibited items before loading onto an aircraft.

Constellis
 12018 Sunrise Valley Drive, Suite 140
 Reston, VA 20191
 Oct 2012 – Dec 2020

I was tasked with the checking and screening of incoming civilians, along with their personal belongings, when entering whichever federal facility I was posted at. It was also my duty to verify the ID of government employees.

Allied Universal
 1760 Market Street
 Philadelphia, PA 19103
 Oct 2012 – Sept 2017

I was tasked with patrolling as well as ensuring the safety of property and personnel at various federal facility locations throughout the Philadelphia region.

United States Marine Corps
 MWSS 472 (-)
 4401 Texas Ave
 Joint Base McGuire-Dix-Lakehurst, NJ 08640
 May 2006 – May 2014

I served two tours of duty (2007-2008 and 2009-2010) in Iraq in support of Operation Iraqi Freedom during which I was tasked with providing a security element on tactical convoy mission's to-and-from forwarding bases or other strategic locations. In addition, I was responsible for issuing and transporting fuel in support of military fixed wing and rotary wing aircrafts. I was also charged with taking account of all fuel issuing and dispensing allocation

EDUCATION:

- Business Administration
 Mercer County Community College, West Windsor, NJ 2009 2013
- Economics
 Rutgers University, New Brunswick, NJ 2013 - 2014

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION:

I am an extremely hardworking, motivated and punctual individual seeking to provide value to a critical, well-structured and dynamic company. I have an exceptional work ethic and positive 'can do' mentality necessary to solve problems while working effectively with others. I believe that I can be a very valuable asset to any team or organization.

.